♪ ♪
And now, with Tami Fields,
it's Spotlight 7 on Atlanta.
Our spotlight tonight
focuses on Atlanta's
most sensational murder.
The victim?
Glamorous international
model, Sally Hitchcock.
Sally was murdered at a party
given by millionaire
socialite, Arthur Richardson,
with whom she had
a torrid two-year affair.
Among party guests that night
were Richardson's
current live-in lover,
former Miss
Georgia, Jan Sinclair.
And Bart Hess, builder
of the famed Hess Tower
funded largely by
Arthur Richardson.
Perhaps not coincidentally,
Hess was also
romantically linked with
doomed beauty, Sally.
Accused of the murder is
noted journalist, David Tanney,
whose exposé of high-level
government corruption
won him national attention,
and a Pulitzer nomination.
In addition, Tanney
was also rumored
to be romantically
involved with the tragic,
but certainly popular, Sally.
Tanney's being defended
by Atlanta's most brilliant
and colorful
attorney, Ben Matlock.
With Tanney's trial
now in its second week,
and with the prosecution
continuing to present
overwhelming evidence
against his client,
it's beginning to look like
Ben Matlock is in the process
of going down in defeat.
So David Tanney
was the last person
to see her alive.
Uh, yes, that's what our
investigation indicates.
And what happened
when you arrived
on the scene, Lieutenant?
Well, first of all, I
saw the defendant
standing between two
private security guards.
Then I discussed the
situation with a patrol officer.
It was decided that a search
of the defendant car
should be conducted.
Show you this vial. It's
marked State Exhibit 22,
and it's labeled
"dimethyl sulfate."
Do you recognize that?
Yes, sir.
This vial was found
under the passenger seat
of the defendant's car.
And what did you do with it?
I personally handed it
to Randall Davis,
head of the crime lab,
for analysis.
Your Honor, in
pursuant to stipulation
with the defense counsel,
I place into evidence,
State's Exhibit 23.
It's a toxicological
report stating that traces
of dimethyl sulfate
were found in the vial.
No further questions.
Your witness.
Thank you.
Lieutenant, my
client's car was found
behind Miss Richardson's
house, is that right?
Yes, it was.
Was it unlocked?
Yes, sir, it was.
Oh, so in the dark that way,
and all those other
cars parked back there,
anybody could've
put that vial of poison
in David Tanney's
car, couldn't they?
Well, uh... Just answer
"yes" or "no," Bob.
Yes, I suppose so.
No further questions.
The prosecution claims to have
an open and shut
case against your client.
Are you worried?
Mr. Matlock, it's not like
you to hide your feelings.
Got any of your, uh,
famous tricks up your sleeve?
If I did, you'd be
the last person
I'd tell in the universe.
Mr. Matlock has every confidence
that his client will
be exonerated.
We're missing something.
Wh-wh-where are those,
uh, witnesses testimonies?
In your briefcase.
Briefcase, yeah, yeah.
But we've been
over and over them.
Well, we're missing it.
Whatever it is,
we're missing it.
Well, either somebody
forgot to tell us something.
Or... we weren't
listening or we didn't ask.
Or we weren't bright
enough to pick it up.
I'll get the car.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute!
Ben, look out!
I don't think you
better move him.
Get an ambulance! Right away.
Oh, Ben... Oh...
Would Nurse Scully
please report to Ward B.
Ben!
How are you feeling?
He's feeling very lucky,
aren't you, Mr. Matlock?
Nothing's broken, just
a sprained shoulder
and some bumps and bruises.
I was thinking of something.
It got away from me.
You're still in shock.
A little rest and you'll
be as good as new.
How long will he be here?
Oh, Doctor's keeping him
for a few days observation.
I'm in the middle
of a murder trial.
Did you ask for a continuance?
Judge Russell refused. Oh.
Said I'm an attorney of
record and we have to go on.
Now, just try to relax.
What's your name? Gertrude.
Well, Gert, you relax.
Take something.
I almost had it.
It was almost there
and it just got away.
And it would've turned the tide.
A good night's
sleep and tomorrow,
everything will be
better, you'll see.
Give me the depositions.
Oh, no-no-no-no-no.
No work while
we're getting well.
Gert!
My name's Gertrude.
Give it!
Give me that briefcase!
Mr. Matlock!
You're my patient.
I'm told bed rest,
and that's what it'll be.
You don't even
go to the bathroom
unless you ring for
me and I help you.
You got that?
Gert, I know you got
an obligation to your patients.
And I'm sure some of them
need to go to the bathroom.
But right now, I
don't need to go.
I need this briefcase.
I've got a client
and he's innocent.
And I almost had it
figured out how to prove it,
but that car knocked
it out of my head.
So I need these depositions.
You're getting upset.
Gert, I'm getting mad.
Don't overdo.
My name's Gertrude.
"At my attorney's request,
"and for his information only,
"I, David Tanney, state
"on the evening of April 12,
"I arrived at Arthur
Richardson's party,
"where Sally Hitchcock
had asked me to meet her.
"She'd promise to
tell me about a scandal
of which she alone
knew the intimate details."
Sir?
Parking over there?
Yes, sir.
"I needed a project.
"I sure needed a new girl.
I was hoping to find
both in one package."
Oh, David!
Glad you could come.
Thanks, Arthur, but, uh,
you didn't invite me.
I'll fire my social secretary.
Jan Sinclair, David Tanney.
David used to work for
me when I owned the Post.
You wrote that book about
military contract payoffs.
You read it?
No. Arthur told me
that you made some very
important people very unhappy.
David's what used to
be called a "muckraker."
Whose muck are you
raking these days, David?
Well, you've caught me
between projects, Arthur.
These days I'm
just crashing parties
and, uh, watching my
bank account shrink.
Well, you're far from poor.
Next to you, Arthur,
everybody's poor.
Champagne?
I'm not drinking.
Nothing serious, I hope.
Allergy medication.
For me, it's a choice between
champagne and sneezing.
Well, I'm sure you know
plenty of people here, David.
Why don't you just
go and enjoy yourself.
Shall we dance, darling?
Nice meeting you, Mr. Tanney.
And you.
May I have a ginger ale, please?
Uh, coming up, sir.
There you are.
Even your best
friends won't know.
"My instincts told me Sally
was bored with men chasing her.
"She wanted to reverse
roles and become the predator.
Better let her come after
me, the willing victim."
Sally!
You look absolutely gorgeous.
That's what I love
about you, David,
because you say
such clever things.
You remember Bart, don't you?
Oh, yes. How are you?
Gee, I didn't know you were
on Arthur's A-list, Danny.
He's on my A-list.
Oh, champagne...
What a good idea.
Get me a glass,
would you, darling?
It's ginger ale, Sal.
Who cares? We got
rid of Bart, didn't we?
Mm.
Oh!
Sally... you are something else.
Well, I'm just so
glad to see you.
Have you checked out
Arthur's new girlfriend?
Yeah, she seems pretty nice.
Oh, she's a slut.
Well, you have to be
to get along with Arthur.
You'd know more
about that than I would.
I'm not jealous, if that's
what you're thinking.
Oh, no, of course not.
You've got Bart.
And here he comes now.
Oh, listen, I will
speak to you later on.
I'll be waiting.
Oh, thank you, darling.
Cheers.
"Time was passing,
and I was no closer
"to the story or to Sally.
"I looked up and spied
her on the landing with Jan
"in what looked like
a heavy argument.
Richardson stopped it." Uh-uh.
You're not arguing
about me, I hope?
You'd just love that,
wouldn't you, Arthur.
What was that all about?
"I moved to intercept her.
"Too late.
"Bart was already there.
"Fortunately, a while later,
she caught up with
me in the library."
There you are.
I've been waiting for you.
Good.
I noticed you and Jan arguing.
Anything I should
be interested in?
I should have known better.
Arthur owns her, the sadist.
That means she's not going
to help you with your article?
Hmm.
Don't worry... I'm
working on her.
What's the problem?
She think Arthur loves her.
He acts like he does.
Oh, yeah?
Then why did he drag
me into his bedroom tonight
and tell me he wanted me
back and then try to seduce me?
Arthur did that?
Mm-hmm. He even gave me this.
Very impressive.
What did you have
to do to get that?
Nothing.
He put it around my
neck and kissed my cheek
and that was that.
I would think that Arthur would
expect a little more in return
for his generosity.
Well, he can expect anything
he wants... he won't get it.
But you could, David.
Anything you want.
And you don't need jewelry.
Sally, you are a very
attractive woman,
but that's not the reason
I came here tonight.
Well, maybe I can
give you another reason.
Hello.
I was looking for you.
I thought you might be thirsty.
Well, you found me. Again.
First with Arthur
and now with, um...
David. Whatever.
Listen, if you two
want to talk, I'll...
No, no, no, I'll go.
That's what Sally wants.
Isn't it, Sally?
Enjoy.
Good night, David.
Have a pleasant evening, Sal.
Take me home with you.
I don't think Bart
would like that much.
But you would.
I promise, David.
I'll get the car.
Oh.
I'll meet you out front.
The guy gave me five bucks...
Excuse me. The red Alpha please.
Yes, sir.
"All right, no story.
"But I wasn't going to
go home empty-handed.
I felt pretty damn good."
Oh, my Lord,
somebody get a doctor...
Mr. Tanney, will you come
back inside with us, please?
Mr. Richardson's orders. What?
You killed her.
No, I didn't.
"I, Arthur Richardson, do
solemnly swear and affirm
"that the following
statement is true and correct.
"I loved parties,
especially my own.
"But I was out of sorts
with Jan that night.
"I couldn't wait to see her face
when Sally Hitchcock arrived."
Keep smiling, darling.
Just a couple of
hundred or so to go.
I can take if you can, darling.
Bart, you're alone.
I'm meeting Sally here.
Sally Hitchcock?
I didn't know she was coming.
You don't mind, do you, darling?
Of course not, darling.
I haven't seen her yet, Bart.
Where's the bar?
I've had the kind of day that
requires some serious unwinding.
Sally darling.
You know Jan.
I feel as if I do.
We have so much in common.
Sally, behave yourself.
Oh, Arthur, in the old days,
you never would have
wanted me to behave myself.
Quite the contrary.
Sally, you look
great. Hello, Bart.
You know Jan?
Of course.
Bart is my oldest
friend in Atlanta.
In fact, he introduced
me to Arthur.
How nice.
Yes. We were living together
at the time, weren't we, Bart?
But Arthur wanted me
and Bart wanted
funding for Hess Towers
so these two did what
businessmen do...
They struck a deal.
Well, that's an interesting
version of ancient history.
Do you want to hear more, Jan?
God no.
You need a drink, darling.
I won't argue with that.
I need to speak to you
in private in a little while.
All right.
Promise? Promise.
What was that about?
I haven't the faintest idea.
Come on, let's dance.
"I had a pretty good idea
what was on Sally's mind,
and I was prepared for it."
What's this about, Sally?
I'm still in love with
you, Arthur. Really?
Well, I'm flattered, of course,
but that's all in the past.
I want you back.
Well, you have heard,
I'm living with Jan.
Jan's no problem.
What do you mean?
I mean I want you.
I don't mind sharing you.
Is that clear enough?
Quite.
But, of course, there's
another small problem.
You affection is no
longer reciprocated.
You can feel my
body this close to you
and still say you
don't want me, Arthur?
It's hard to believe, isn't it?
Impossible.
I love Jan very, very much
and I've no desire
to cheat on her.
At least, not yet.
And not with someone
I've already had.
You have a very charming way
of expressing yourself, Arthur.
Now don't be offended, Sally.
I've got a little
something for you.
A souvenir of our relationship.
A final souvenir.
Oh, this is a payoff, Arthur?
A trinket?
Well, have a look before
you turn your nose up at it.
Arthur!
Here. A little something
to remember us by.
Oh.
Let's see what it
looks like on you.
Oh, Arthur, it's beautiful.
It's almost as beautiful
as you are, my dear.
And now I think it's time
that we get back to the party.
Mr. Matlock.
Oh, hello, Gert.
Oh, look at this.
You're into mischief.
Just working.
You have been to the bathroom
without calling for
me, haven't you?
Well, I went just a little bit.
How'd you know?
I know the type.
Gert, don't do that.
I have those depositions
just the way I need them.
Now it's going to take hours
to get them back
the way they were.
Don't you have any
sick people to tend to?
I told the doctor about you,
and he said no work or else.
Or else what?
Or else a little of
this or a little of that.
Maybe even a little shot.
You tell that doctor to bring
anything he wants to in here.
I'll take him to his knees
and I'll hurt him every
way from Sunday
and then we'll
see about no work.
Mr. Matlock!
Gert, I'm working
on a murder case.
Murder one.
The only thing standing
between my client
and the maximum sentence
is the best defense
I can prepare,
and that's what I'm
doing, okay, Gert?
Would you like pineapple
juice or nonfat egg-less custard?
Custard.
Hey, Gert.
Two scoops.
Hmm.
Oh, really...?
Now, ladies, not
arguing about me I hope.
Oh, you would just love
that, wouldn't you, Arthur?
What was that all about?
Just Sally being a bitch.
Sally was being Sally
and Bart, who should have
known better, was clearly furious.
My God, she's dead.
Call the police.
Where's Tanney? He
was just in here with her.
Find him.
Lights out.
Oh, come on, Gert.
You need your sleep.
Gert, give me a break.
Your doctor ordered
complete rest.
He'll be very unhappy with you.
Gert, you bring
that doctor in here,
I'll throw his hind end
through that window
and he'll be very
unhappy with you.
Well, maybe tomorrow.
But tonight, it's lights out.
Oh, Gert.
No. Good night, Mr. Matlock.
Good night, Gert.
Gertrude.
Mr. Matlock.
You're in deep trouble, Gert.
I, Barton Hess, do
solemnly swear and affirm
that the following
statement is true and correct.
Evening, sir.
I couldn't wait to see Sally.
We were getting along so well,
like old times, only better.
Bart. Oh.
You're alone?
Uh, I'm meeting Sally here.
Sally Hitchcock?
I didn't know she was coming.
Well, yes.
You don't mind, do you, darling?
Of course not, darling.
She hasn't arrived yet, Bart.
Tell her I'm here,
will you, Arthur?
It's nice to see you, Jan.
Arthur. Sally.
How are you? Good.
Oh, Bart, sweetheart.
You look... delicious.
Oh, do you know Jan?
Of course.
Bart is my oldest
friend in Atlanta.
In fact, he introduced
me to Arthur.
Um, it's ancient history.
You want to hear more, Jan?
Not really.
Except that he's also
my dearest friend.
Well, thank you, sweetheart.
That deserves champagne.
Oh, I'd love some.
In the old days, I
would have been uneasy
seeing them together, but
I pushed aside any doubts.
What was that all about?
What? Arthur.
Oh. What did he want?
He said he wanted
to talk to me later.
Oh? About what?
I don't know.
It is over between
you and him, isn't it?
Of course it is, darling.
Don't be silly.
I am right where
I belong: with you.
Excuse me, Miss Hitchcock.
I won't be long, darling.
I knew she was
going to see Arthur.
Some men would have been angry,
but I prided myself
on my equanimity.
Besides, I trusted
Sally completely.
Sally!
I noticed there was
something different immediately.
A necklace.
I decided not to
ask Sally about it,
but to let her tell me.
Hi.
I need some champagne.
What did he want?
You won't believe this.
About Arthur? I'd
believe anything.
He made a pass at me.
Isn't that bizarre?
What do you mean?
I mean, he tried to
seduce me, darling.
The gold treatment.
He said he missed me.
He said he thought
about me constantly,
wished we were still together.
Oh, then he kissed me.
And, how do I put this?
He, um... He wouldn't let me go.
What did you say?
I said I loved you,
and that our
relationship was serious
and I'd never do
anything to jeopardize it.
How did he take that?
Pretty well, actually.
But then, what could he do?
I mean, he knew I
meant exactly what I said.
And just to prove there were
no hard feelings, he gave me this.
That's a parting gift, I hope.
For old times' sake.
Well, Arthur's got style.
I'll give him that.
Sally.
Hello, David.
Excuse me. Sally, you
look absolutely gorgeous.
Thank you. You
remember Bart, don't you?
Oh, yes, hi. How are you?
Fine. How about you?
Just fine.
Sally, we must talk.
Um... That's my
cue for champagne.
Thank you,
sweetheart. Hurry back.
I wondered what
they were talking about
and then I reminded myself,
"I trust Sally completely."
Here you are, darling.
Oh, thank you, sweetheart.
David was just telling me
about investigative reporting.
Oh, the fine art of the exposé.
Whose trail are you hot on now?
No one.
But I am open to suggestions.
Well, it's time
for me to mingle.
I'll see you later.
Abrupt, isn't he?
Oh, yeah, somewhat of a hustler.
Oh? Was he hustling you?
No, not really. He
was just asking me
reporter type questions.
I suspect he thinks
I have secrets to tell.
You're joking.
Yes.
Shall we dance? Mmm.
Not arguing about me, I hope.
You'd just love that,
wouldn't you, Arthur?
Sally.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
I think it's something.
Jan's jealous and
taking it out on me.
And why is she jealous?
Jealousy is a way of life
when you live with a
man as unfaithful as Arthur.
Ah. Whatever you say, darling.
What's this?
Another little gift from Arthur.
He scratched me when he
was putting on the necklace
and then he insisted
on a bandage.
Well, you know how
phobic he is about germs.
Yes, Arthur does have
his, uh, idiosyncrasies.
Tell me about it.
Hi! I thought you
might be thirsty.
I brought along some
of my private stock.
Oh, thank you,
sweetheart. That's so sweet.
Oh, where's you're glass, David?
Actually, Sally and
I were just talking.
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't
mean to interrupt.
You didn't.
David is just being rude.
No, no. I understand completely.
Um... Enjoy the champagne.
And the evening.
See you later, Sally.
What happened?
She's dead.
Call the police.
David Tanney.
He was just in here with her.
Get him.
You killed her.
Good morning.
Oh, hi, Gert.
Gertrude.
How did you sleep?
Fine, fine, fine, fine, fine.
Well, you sound a
little more chipper today.
Oh, yeah, I feel good.
A little headache, but...
Oh, well, we can
take care of that.
Yeah?
What's that, a mustard plaster?
It's a patch.
Don't you have
any headache pills?
This is better than a pill.
It doesn't upset your stomach
and it keeps
working much longer.
The medication is in the bandage
and it leeches into the skin
a little at a time by osmosis.
You know what
osmosis is, don't you
I did in high school.
Give me your arm.
Osmosis.
Gert... I love you.
Now, do this, Michelle.
Catch her the minute
she gets to the courthouse.
Get her off by herself.
Because she won't talk to you
if Arthur Richardson is around.
Okay? Okay.
Oh, hi, Charlie.
I thought maybe
you'd get in early today.
Morning, Ben, what
happened to you?
I got hit by a car.
Damn crazy drivers.
You know, a cousin of
mine just got hit by a car.
No, no, it was my fault.
I got absentminded and I wasn't
watching where I was going.
You got to be careful, Ben.
I wouldn't like to see
you in here as a customer,
if you know what I mean.
Yeah.
Yeah... Boy, you're
running out of space.
Dead people leave
a lot of stuff behind.
You know, the corpus delicti
go in an ice box down the hall.
Everything else
winds up in here.
Well, that's why I
stopped by, Charlie.
Um... You want to turn around?
I, uh... I'm stuck on a case,
and I think there may be a
piece of evidence I missed.
Well, the DA's office
keeps the real evidence.
All I got is odds and
ends and leftover junk.
Well, that may be just
exactly what I'm looking for.
Here-Here's the
case... the case number.
Can I turn around?
Turn around.
Oh, excuse me.
Ben, how are you feeling?
Oh, I feel fine.
You look awful.
I do?
Yes. Terrible.
Did you talk to Jan?
Yeah, you were right.
Yeah? Yeah.
Do you know what I
was trying to think of
when that car hit me?
Yeah. Did you figure it out?
Yep.
In the hospital, I
had such a headache
from the... from the
accident and from reading
all those depositions, and
this nurse cured it for me.
Wonderful woman. Oh...
Yeah, and that's
what did it, yeah.
Did what? Yeah.
Did what?
Court will come to order.
Court is pleased to see
Mr. Matlock back with us so soon.
Glad to be back, Your Honor.
I apologize for my appearance.
If you're ready to proceed,
you may call your first witness.
Thank you.
Uh, I call Arthur
Richardson to the stand,
and, uh, since he's already
testified for the prosecution,
I request permission
to examine him
as a hostile witness
during his testimony.
Permission granted.
Proceed, Mr. Matlock.
Mr. Richardson, for several
months before she was killed,
you were having an
affair with Sally Hitchcock,
isn't that right?
It was no secret, yes.
Yep. And even after
the affair was over,
you, um, as they
say, uh, kept in touch?
Oh, yes.
I even invited
her to my parties.
Why did you invite
to your parties?
She was beautiful, charming,
and I was very fond of her.
Mm, mm.
Did you know that, uh...
she was planning to write
one of those magazine
articles on you?
Sally? Write?
Obviously, you
didn't know Sally.
No, no, I didn't, but, uh...
lesser lights than
Miss Hitchcock
have been published.
All she needed was a
ghostwriter and something to say,
and she had...
Objection: relevance.
Sustained. Sally
had nothing to say.
She had plenty to say.
She was with you all the time.
She knew all about
you, didn't she?
I resent the insinuation.
There's no insinuation.
You keep a very high profile.
A lot of good-looking women,
a lot of money, lot
of powerful people.
And, uh... she knew
all about your, uh...
exploits... and,
well, idiosyncrasies.
Didn't she?
Mr. Matlock, I may be rich
and I may throw
extravagant parties.
But I'm a very ordinary person
with a very uninteresting
personal life.
Anybody who suggests
otherwise may find them self
constrained to prove
those allegations in court.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
and that's what,
that's what David
Tanney told her, wasn't it?
He told her that she had to
have all her stories on you
independently corroborated
or no publisher
would touch them,
and that's what she was
talking with Jan about...
Corroboration, wasn't it?
Well, you'll have to
ask Jan about that.
Didn't Jan tell you
that she was trying to
get corroboration on her?
Jan said no such thing.
She didn't?
Huh. She didn't?
My associate subpoenaed
her just this morning
after you had come
in the courthouse
before you had a
chance to speak with her.
Are you sure she
wouldn't say...?
Well, she might have mentioned
something along
those lines, I...
Along what lines?
Something about some of
the things that happened.
I don't know; I didn't
pay that much attention.
No, no, no, you didn't.
You didn't have to...
because you knew.
Sally Hitchcock was
blackmailing you, wasn't she?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
And that's why she
was at the party.
She was there because
she had a pretty face.
That's what the
meeting was about
up in your bedroom,
wasn't it: blackmail.
No.
And the big payoff was that
expensive necklace, wasn't it?
Objection: relevancy;
badgering the witness.
Sustained. Your Honor,
I have gone through
every piece of testimony
by every witness in this trial,
and they're all
partly the truth.
Some are complete,
some are incomplete.
Some are partial,
some are impartial.
But they're all inconsistent
with one another.
We will find out what
happened that night,
but I must beg the
court's indulgence, please.
Proceed.
Thank you.
Now... that meeting...
Talk... that you had with Sally
up in, up in your bedroom,
you were the only witness
to that conversation, right?
Sadly.
Why did you give
her that necklace?
Just a little memento
for old time's sake.
Oh, boy, that's gallant.
I'm talking about
gallant, gallant.
And did you put it
around her neck?
Yes, as a matter of fact.
And when you put it on her,
you scratched her neck
a little bit, didn't you?
No.
Well, people at the party
saw her when she came down
from the bedroom, said that...
that she had a little patch
on the back of her neck.
I don't remember that.
Well, it's right here...
in, uh, in the People's
autopsy report.
See right here?
Look right there.
"A small laceration on the
back of the decedent's neck."
I just don't recall that.
Yeah.
Well, uh, do you, do
you remember, uh...
do you remember being
in-in-in the bathroom with her
while she was admiring
the necklace in the mirror?
You told the police that
you were and it was
in your deposition.
Well, she wanted to look
at the necklace in the mirror.
Of course, you had a
big mirror in the bedroom
and plenty of light.
You took her in the
bathroom because you wanted
to put a bandage on
that scratch, didn't you?
Oh, yes, yes.
Uh, I didn't recall
that at the time.
You're right, I did, indeed.
Your Honor, I have
a continuing relevancy
objection to all of these questions.
Your Honor, please?
You need to move
on, Mr. Matlock.
We are, Your Honor, we are.
Uh, traces of poison were found
in the decedent's
champagne glass.
And the police assumed
that's what killed her.
But that poison could
have been put in that glass
by people who entered the
room after she had collapsed,
and you were one
of them, weren't you?
Yes.
But why would I do
something like that?
To cover your tracks.
To throw off the police.
Because, in fact...
you had poisoned her
several hours
before, hadn't you?
That's impossible!
I know.
I thought so, too.
I couldn't figure it out.
I just couldn't figure it out.
I brooded over it.
I, finally, I was hit by a car.
I had to go to the hospital.
See?
I had this awful headache.
And this nurse,
this wonderful, beautiful
nurse... Gertrude...
She cured it for me.
She, she, she gave me what
she called a "medication patch."
I'd never seen
anything like that before.
It's like a bandage that's
impregnated with medication.
And you put it on, and it
goes through your system
slowly over a
long period of time.
And, finally, it finds the
pain and takes it away.
Your Honor,
now Mr. Matlock
is testifying for us.
But, Your Honor,
my headache's gone.
Isn't that wonderful?
What does that have
to do with this case?
It has everything to
do with it, Your Honor.
Don't you see
that Mr. Richardson
was able to kill
Sally Hitchcock by
delayed reaction.
And it shows me
that you were
able to put yourself
in the clear when
the poison took effect.
This is ridiculous.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
The bandage!
You put poison in the bandage,
and it's right here.
I got it at the
coroner's office.
See? See?
There.
Nobody paid any attention to it
because they didn't
think it was important.
Thank God they
didn't throw it away
or we would never
have known, would we?
You put...
dimethyl sulfate
on that bandage...
and you put it on
the back of her neck.
Then you took her by the arm,
smiled at her, took
her back to the party.
And when she
walked away from you,
you knew the poison
was seeping slowly
through her body.
And it's getting stronger
and stronger and stronger,
and when you were in a
whole nother part of the house,
it seized her, collapsed
her breathing...
and she collapsed and died.
You killed her...
and this proves it.
Nothing further.
We find the defendant
David Tanney not guilty.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
This court is adjourned.
Thanks, Mr. Matlock.
Thank you, Ms.
Thomas; thank you.
Well, great job, Ben.
Michelle... Hmm?
Do me a favor.
Take this hospital
gown and give it to Gert.
She'll know what it means.
www.tvsubtitles.net